Edoardo Gargano

Full-stack senior developer, JavaScript and Typescript

via A. Bergamini 6, 40133, Bologna, IT

edoardo.gargano@gmail.com \$\mathbb{1}\$ +39 329 54 166 26

© Edoardo Gargano in Edoardo Gargano

Full-stack developer, 15 years experienced front-end developer, tech lead for almost 10 years, JavaScript and Typescript lover, and 'Bologna JS' Community Organizer.

After successfully completing my Master's Degree in Computer Science at the University of Bologna, I worked for 3 years as a full-stack developer at CINECA. Since 2011, I have worked in the technology department of YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP, leading a front-end development team.

After my YNAP experience where I grew a lot, I worked in Robin company as a full-stack developer, writing a multitenant frontend platform serving 4 newspapers.

From 2021 I'm in Paramount International, a network streaming area, working on a big monorepo in React serving more than 20 websites for super famous TV like MTV, NickJunior, BETPlus, and many others.

I also like 'clean code' and an agile way of work.

I have good experience managing technical teams, understanding people, and maintaining high-quality code standards. I'm searching for projects where I can do first-class web software, in a clean and organized way, putting my experience as a technician to deliver fast, do tests, work on the maintainability of software and with great performance.

I like open-minded workplaces with a strong company culture based on respect and motivation.

I work very well in full-remote because I like to collaborate with my team and listen/speak with them in pair or mob programming.

SKILLS

Web Development Master	Leadership Master	Master	Frameworks Advanced
javascript typescript html/html5 scss/css analysis	team management and support teamwork problem solving time management	web vitals pwa lazy loading code splitting ssr/static generation	reactjs vuejs redux/vuex jest testing library cypress gatsby san strapi stripe
Testing Advanced	Software Engineering Advanced	Database Advanced	Agile Advanced
tdd bdd functional test integration test	programming language design pattersq! nosql (mongodb, dynamo) pl/sqsçrum kanban agile ceremonies scalability analysis cloud/serverless ^r edis software architecture		

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-stack developer at T4Project - contractor @ Paramount International (full-remote) **10/2021 - Today** https://www.paramount.com/

I'm working on the migration of a Web TV (live channels, video on demand) to one of Paramount's streaming platforms. We are an international team working mostly in the CEST time zone.

My everyday job is writing code in React, server, and client, optimizing performance, getting data from the backend with an internal solution similar to GraphQL, and coordinating with other teams to maintain and develop the platform based on a big monorepo.

As a Senior developer, here's what I do:

- Learn something new, everyday
- Work on large-scale, custom-designed, enterprise-level software development projects.
- Work with Scrum framework
- Mentor Junior members to improve their skills
- Create tests for new functionalities and migrate the existing ones to modern test approaches
- Understand dependencies and modify/create libraries for everyday needs
- Help the platform team to improve the framework and tools from developer feedback
- Participate in meeting with iOS, Android, Connected TV, Roku, and API to be aligned on request and deliver fast
- An European web TV with 4 channels

Key Responsibilities

- Developing with quality #PROGRAMMING
- Developing testing strategies #TESTING
- Defining best practices to keep high software performances #PERFORMANCE
- Designing the evolutions of software products #EVOLUTION
- Refactor old tools and services #REFACTOR
- Leading planning activities and supporting predictability #AGILE
- Defining and steering technical strategy with technical leads and architects#STRATEGY
- Supporting Project Managers #SUPPORT
- Team coaching and mentoring through workshops #MENTORING

Technologies

- HTML5, CSS3, JS/TS
- React SSR/Client, Vanilla Js, Webpack, Node.js, Nx Monorepo
- REST API

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-stack developer at Robin - MONRIF group (Bologna) 07/202010/2021

https://www.monrif.it/

Robin needs someone that has a strong experience in JS/TS to write new applications with this technology in front and backend.

They also need someone with leadership experience to mentor actual colleagues and create some teams, with also some external contractors.

In my workday I write code creating, maintaining, and evolving software used by our newspaper, from the new frontend platform (React, Next.js, Typescript) to the new CMS created with Strapi and Typescript.

As a Senior developer, here's what I do:

- Learn something new, everyday
- Work on large-scale, custom-designed, enterprise-level software development projects using JavaScript language and technologies.
- Champion agile best practices and Continuous Delivery
- Help the team to champion software excellence, craft technical vision, and ensure we deliver value to our clients and their customers.
- Experience working with agile, Lean, and/or Continuous Delivery approaches and best practices, such as Continuous Integration, TDD, BDD, etc.
- Knowledge of software best practices like Refactoring, Clean Code, Domain Driven Design, and Encapsulation.
- Openness and adaptability you'll be working in a variety of settings and in a team-oriented, collaborative environment
- A coaching mentality as well as strong relationship-building skills at all levels
- DB: MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, NoSQL
- https://www.ilrestodelcarlino.it/
- https://www.ilgiorno.it/
- https://www.lanazione.it/
- https://www.quotidiano.net/

Key Responsibilities

- Leading projects #LEAD
- Developing with quality #PROGRAMMING
- Developing testing strategies #TESTING
- Defining best practices to keep high software performances #PERFORMANCE
- Designing the evolutions of software products #EVOLUTION
- Refactor old tools and services #REFACTOR
- Leading planning activities and supporting in predictability #AGILE
- Defining and steering technical strategy with technical leads and architects#STRATEGY
- Supporting Project Managers #SUPPORT
- Team coaching and mentoring through workshops #MENTORING

Technologies

HTML5, CSS3, JS/TS

- React, Vanilla Js, Webpack, Node.is, Python
- NoSQL DB, Relational DB (Oracle, MySQL, Microsoft SQL)
- Strapi, Ghost, Stripe, Sanity, Gatsby, Next.js
- Git, Agile, Bash, AWS, Google Cloud

Front-End Tech Lead at YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP (Bologna) 2013 - 06/2020

https://www.ynap.com

My daily job is relative to team management, programming, planning, analysis of new functionalities and website performance enhancement, ensuring technical cohesion across the domain teams, and acting as the technical domain representative in cross-domain matters.

My team is in charge of the following three luxury e-commerce websites, with a focus on the development of new features, integration, and refactorization of existing features, and measuring and optimizing the website performances:

- https://www.balenciaga.com/
- https://www.alexandermcqueen.com/
- https://www.mcg.com/

Key Responsibilities

- Leading a front-end development team #LEAD
- Developing in a number of programming languages, with quality #PROGRAMMING
- Developing testing strategies #TESTING
- Defining best practices to keep high software performances #PERFORMANCE
- Designing the evolutions of software products #EVOLUTION
- Leading planning activities and supporting in predictability #AGILE
- Defining and steering technical strategy with technical leads and architects#STRATEGY
- Supporting Project Managers and Product Managers #SUPPORT
- Team coaching and mentoring through workshops and communities #MENTORING

Technologies

- HTML5, CSS3, JS
- React, Vue.js and relative ecosystem
- NoSQL DB, Relational DB (Oracle, MySQL, Microsoft SQL)
- C#, RAZOR, MVC framework
- Website performance optimization
- Agile

Front-End Developer (Consultant) at YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP (Bologna) 2011 - 2013

https://www.ynap.com

As consultant, I was in charge of the development and maintenance of e-commerce websites powered by YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP.

Main activities

- Restyling of existing websites and adding new features and functionalities
- Front-End optimization (pixel perfection from layouts,...) and mapping and skinning functionalities from backend side
- Bug fixing
- Web performance optimization
- Technologies used: ASP, HTML5, CSS (CSS3), JavaScript, XSL, MVC Razor, Agile

PHP Developer and Web developer at CINECA (Bologna) 2009 - 2011

https://cineca.it

I started my professional career developing web applications working with PHP and Oracle Databases.

Main activities

- Development of web applications for clinical trials and pharmaceutical procedures
- Creation and maintenance of the internal Help Desk application
- Development of corporate websites in Drupal and Wordpress

VOLUNTEER

Organiser at Bologna JavaScript Community/Meetup

2015 - Today

https://bolognajs.com/

BolognaJS is a community for JavaScript developers in Bologna. We made workshops, talks, networking meetings, we believe in sharing knowledge and we study new technologies on JavaScript ecosystem. I love to meet people and to

speak about Programming features, techniques doing something together.

See our last meetup on: https://www.meetup.com/Bologna-JS-Meetup/

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Computer Science at University of Bologna (UniBo) **2005 - 2008**

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science at University of Bologna (UniBo) **2001 - 2005**

LANGUAGES

Italian

Native speaker

English

Fluent

REFERENCES

Nicola Cuccurazzu

Senior Product Owner, YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP

Very competent in web sphere and it's pleasant to work with him 'cause he is able to mix seriousness and professionalism with a great deal of sympathy.

Giuseppe Mandato

Software Engineer, Elsevier

I've had the privilege of working with Edoardo for a couple of months, I joined its team in a very stressful period, the project deadline was strict and the company had large expectations. Despite everything Edoardo made the journey like a peaceful walk, thanks to its technical and relational skills we met the deadline and it was even funny. I was impressed by the trust he has given me. Absolutely one of the best Tech Lead I ever had.